Transcript and translation
from pokeyou66 http://youtu.be/qOODX5iRzag
Sung by Jobelle Ubalde (白珍寶)
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
寒風冰山將心窩都冷凍
hon fung bing saan zeng sam wo dou laang dung
The cold winds and icy mountains freeze my heart
not a footprint to be seen
冰山冰鋒　彷似夢
bing saan bing fung fong ci mung
These icy peaks seem like a dream
A kingdom of isolation,
就像墜落在世界外
zau zeng do lok zoi sai gaai ngoi
It feels like I've fallen out of this world,
and it looks like I'm the queen
放眼雪山　一片空
fong ngaan syut saan yat pin hung
As I look around and see nothing but emptiness
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
陣陣冷風撲面刺痛天際亂碰
zan zan laang fung pok min ci tung tin zai lyun pung
My face is stung by the cold winds as they blow across the sky
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
此刻心更慌　驚慌擾惡夢
ci hak sam gang fong ging fong yiu ok mung
Now my heart panics even more, which disturbs this bad dream
Don't let them in, don't let them see
誰曾勸我　逃離心魔
sui cang hyun ngo tou lei sam mo
I've been told that to escape from my inner demons,
Be the good girl you always had to be
不惹紛爭　唯憑善意輔助
bat ye fan zang wai pang sin yi fu zo
Don't attract trouble by relying on others for help
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
埋藏以往　遺忘當初
maai cong yi wong wai mong dong co
Bury the past, forget the start,
Well, now they know!
遺忘自我
wai mong zi ngo
Forget myself!
Let it go, let it go!
忘掉那　無形鎖
mong diu naa mou ying so
Forget that invisible lock
Can't hold it back any more!
我才能完全是我
ngo coi nang yun cyun si ngo
I'll finally be able to be myself
Let it go, let it go!
誰亦要　隨心歌
sui yik yiu cui sam go
Who else wants to follow their heart?
Turn away and slam the door!
誰願陷落於心鎖
sui yun ham lok yu sam so
Who'd want to fall into their heart's lock?
I don't care what they're going to say
不必躲　旁人休得管我
bat bit do pong yan yau dak gun ngo
There's no need to hide from those that try to control me
Let the storm rage on
我拒絕諧和
ngo kui zyut haai wo
I refuse to let things be
The cold never bothered me anyway.
自信冷酷也未必傷到我
zi seon laang huk yaa mei bit seng dou ngo
I'm confident the cold can't hurt me
It's funny how some distance
當初驚天的一切
dong co ging tin dik yat cai
All the things that I once feared,
Makes everything seem small
如今都變爛泥
yu gam dou bin laan nai
Have all been turned to slush
And the fears that once controlled me
繁文共律例也失去
faan man gung leot lai yaa sat hui
Those complicated rules and regulations have lost
Can't get to me at all!
往昔一般天威
wong sik yat bun tin wai
the power they once had!
It's time to see what I can do
回頭看我如何發揮
wui tau hon ngo yu ho faat fai
Look back and see what I can do,
To test the limits and break through
似衝破法規與天齊
ci cung po faat kwai yu tin cai
Break the rules and break through to the sky
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
全無禁制　忘記常規
cyun mou gam zai mong gei seng kwai
Nothing is off-limits, forget those rules
I'm free!
限制
haan zai
and limitations
Let it go, let it go!
忘掉那　無形鎖
mong diu naa mou ying so
Forget that invisible lock,
I am one with the wind and sky
去又來昂然而自我
hui yau loi ngong yin yi zi ngo
Whereever I go, I will proudly be myself
Let it go, let it go!
誰亦要　隨心歌
sui yik yiu cui sam go
Who else wants to follow their heart?
You'll never see me cry
忘掉昨天悲歌
mong diu zok tin bei go
Forget the sad songs of yesterday
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
我是誰　全新的我
ngo si sui cyun san dik ngo
Who am I? The brand new me.
Let the storm rage on...
要拒絕諧和
yiu kui zyut haai wo
Refuses to let things be
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
我用我能力奏出冰天的贊歌
ngo yung ngo nang lik zau ceot bing tin dik zaan go
I use my powers to perform a song praising the icy skies
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
我內裡藏著潛力翻出不世的風波
ngo noi lui cong zek cim lik faan ceot bat sai dik fung bo
I have the potential inside of me to create an everlasting storm
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
看著我前路變色冰封千里多
hon zek ngo zin lou bin sik bing fung cin lei do
Watch as the path ahead of me is frozen for miles and miles
I'm never going back
闖新天一個我
cong san tin yat go ngo
As I head towards a new day,
The past is in the past!
再不要攔住我
zoi bat yiu laan zyu ngo
I won't be held back any more!
Let it go, let it go!
放棄吧　無形鎖
fong hei baa mou ying so
Give up that invisible lock
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
再度黎明重頭活過
zoi dou lai ming cung tau wut gwo
When dawn breaks, a new life awaits
Let it go, let it go!
誰亦要　隨心歌
sui yik yiu cui sam go
Who else wants to follow their heart?
That perfect girl is gone
毋用避開心魔
mou yung bei hoi sam mo
No need to hide from what's inside
Here I stand in the light of day
我是誰　還原於心火
ngo si sui waan yun yu sam fo
Who am I? Restore the fire to my heart
Let the storm rage on!
我放任寒風
ngo fong yam hon fung
I set the cold winds free!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
自信冷酷冷酷傷不到我
zi seon laang huk laang huk seng bat dou ngo
I'm confident the cold can't hurt me at all.